If you are either a beginner or an expert in object-oriented programming
あなたがオブジェクト指向プログラミングの初心者でも あるいはエキスパートでも、
you will love this MOOC because it will change the way you program with objects.
この MOOC が気にいるでしょう。なぜなら オブジェクトでプログラミングする方法を変えてしまうからです。
I am Stéphane Ducasse, with Luc Fabresse and Damien Cassou,
私はステファン・デュカス。そして、 リュック・ファブレス と ダミアン・カスーです。
we will present this MOOC about Pharo.
私たちがこの Pharo の MOOC の講師を務めます。
What is Pharo?
Pharo とは何か？
Pharo is a dynamic and pure language that will offer you
Pharo は、動的で純粋な言語で、 あなたに
a unique development experience in which you will be
ユニークな開発体験をもたらします。 そこであなたは
in constant interaction with live objects.
生きたオブジェクトと 常に対話をするでしょう。
Pharo is a language and an open source environment in the tradition of Smalltalk.
Pharo は1つの言語であり、かつ、Smalltalkの伝統に則った オープンソースの環境です。
It is fun to use, elegant and very powerful.
使っていて楽しく、 エレガントで、そして、とても強力です。
Why do I say that Pharo is elegant?
なぜ Pharo はエレガントなのかというと、
In fact, it is very simple: its full syntax, and I insist
シンプルだからです。 構文規則全体が…いいですか、
on “full”, can be written on a postcard and its object-oriented
「全体が」ですよ、1枚のハガキに 書けてしまうのです。そしてオブジェクト指向の
model written in 4 lines. Moreover, Pharo and its environment are
モデルが4行で書けます。 さらに、Pharo とその環境は
written in Pharo itself exclusively with objects and messages.
Pharo 自身で記述されています。 オブジェクトとメッセージだけで。
All these points make Pharo very easy to learn and
だから Pharo を学ぶのは 簡単です。そして
once you have understood the syntax, you will have access to
一旦構文を理解したら、 あなたは Pharo の世界全体に
the whole Pharo world, hence it is written in Pharo itself.
アクセスすることができます。 Pharo は Pharo 自身で記述されているからです。
That is why Pharo is used in about thirty
それが Pharo が 世界の30の大学で
universities all over the world to teach object-oriented programing.
オブジェクト指向プログラミングを 教えるために使われている理由です。
In this MOOC, you will discover that Pharo is fun.
このMOOCで、あなたは Pharo の楽しさを発見するでしょう。
In fact, when programing in Pharo, you are immersed in a world of
実際、Pharo でプログラミングしていると、 あなたは生きたオブジェクトの世界に
live objects. Each time the programer modifies
没入するのです。プログラマが コードを修正するたびに
its code, the 3D animation changes and he can see immediately
3Dアニメーションが変化して 直ちにプログラムの結果を
the result of its program.
見ることができます。
In Pharo, the programer modifies continuously objects with immediate feedback.
Pharo では、プログラマはオブジェクトを修正したら 直ちにフィードバックを得ることができます。
These objects can represent web applications, graphics in 2D,
ウェブアプリケーションや 2次元や3次元のグラフィックスや
in 3D, network, or even code itself.
ネットワークや、コード自身さえも そういったオブジェクトで表現されています。
You will see that in Pharo everything is object.
Pharo では全てがオブジェクトなのです。
In this MOOC, you will discover that Pharo is also a powerful
この MOOC では、Pharoはまた、 様々な企業でも使われている言語だと
language, used in companies.
いうことを理解するでしょう。
And you can discover some success stories
いくつかの成功事例は Pharo のウェブサイトで
on Pharo’s website.
見ることができます。
In this MOOC, we will also present Pharo’s web stack.
この MOOC では、Pharo の ウェブスタックを説明します。
and how this stack revolutionizes the way web applications
このスタックがウェブアプリケーションの 設計を革命的に変えていることを
are designed. During this MOOC, you will deploy
あなたは理解するでしょう。 この MOOC を通じて、あなたは
a web application fully written in Pharo.
全てがPharoで記述されたウェブアプリケーションを デプロイすることになるでしょう。
Beyond this, we will revisit fundamental principles
さらに、我々は、 プログラミングの基礎原理に立ち返って
of programing by illustrating how Pharo uses them.
Pharo がそれに則っていることを示します。
We will present some coding idioms and design patterns
ウェブアプリケーションのより良い設計のための コーディングのイディオムや
to better design web applications.
デザインパターンを示します。
Such concepts can be applied to any object-oriented language
それらの概念は、Pharo だけでなく あらゆるオブジェクト指向言語に
beyond Pharo.
適用できます。
Moreover, you will have access to many resources such as
さらに、あなたは沢山の資料への アクセスを得るでしょう。たとえば
the book “Pharo by example” which is available on Pharo’s website.
「Pharo by Example」という書籍は Pharo のウェブサイトで入手できます。
For the most experienced of you, this MOOC will provide a new
エキスパート向けには、 この MOOC はオブジェクト指向プログラミングの
vision of the fundamental principles of object-oriented programming
基礎原理の新しい見方を示します。
(i.e. late binding and polymorphism).
(例えば、遅延束縛や 多態性です)
Through out this MOOC come and discover or rediscover object-oriented
この MOOC に参加して、 今までと違うオブジェクト指向プログラミング
programing in a different world, the world of Pharo…
Pharoの世界を発見、または、再発見して みませんか？